Teresa Bembury

Promotional
Print and Web
Design/Production

Hands-on skills:

Adobe CS5
(InDesign, Photoshop,
Bridge, Illustrator,
Acrobat, Dreamweaver)
Microsoft Office Suite,
XHTML, CSS, XML,
CMS (Wordpress),
JavaScript jQuery,
Basic Flash

Developing skills: Javascript, HTML5,

teresa.bembury @gmail.com

http://www. bemburydesigns.net

C.732-822-0225 H. 662-4046

SKILL SUMMARY

Successful background working in fast-paced creative environments with progressive responsibilities from production management to design to art direction. Experience involved conceptualizing and following through on winning design concepts for catalogs, direct-mail packages, promotional print and web campaigns. Worked in all phases of design and production to support marketing initiatives.

WORK HISTORY

Visionflow

Print and Web Design Specialist 2012 – Present

Organize, coordinate and manage print and web design projects for profit and non-profit institutions. *Projects includes*; annual reports, brochures, posters, print ads, web design and development, web banner design, email blast campaigns.

Key Accountabilities:

- concept development, design and layout
- creative presentation
- research/purchase illustrations and photos
- photoshop retouching and color correction
- PSDto XHTML, CSS
- development of CMS Wordpress
- JavaScript library/ jQuery
- semantic layout techniques

Direct Brands, Inc. (formerly Columbia House, BMG Music, Doubleday)

Sr. Art Director/ Designer 2005 – 2011 **Art Director/Designer** 2001 – 2005 Experiences involved conceptualizing and following through on winning design concepts for catalogs, promotional web campaigns, direct-mail packages, ancillary projects, while working

directly with Creative Directors, Editorial, Copywriters, Marketing and Production.

Key Accountabilities:

- Concept development, layout & design of six magazine-style catalog
- Concept development, layout & design of direct-mail packages
- Creative presentation
- Supervised free-lancers
- Researched and purchased illustrations & photos
- Accessing content via CMS database
- Created, maintained templates & style sheets

- Responsible for adapting test versions of controls
- Ensured that creative consistently supported the brands vision
- Retouching and color correction of high-res images
- Directed in-house photography
- Sign-of on printer proofs

Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. (subsidiary of Time-Warner)

Design Studio Manager 1996 – 2001

Organized, coordinated and managed studio team in production process of front-end direct-mail packages catalogs, and print advertising for direct- to consumer book clubs. Worked directly with Creative Directors and outside agencies to assure integrity of design through production process.

Key Accountabilities:

- · oversaw freelance and intern team
- responsible for creating direct-mail test versions
- directed set-up shots for in-house photographer
- creating, maintaining templates and style sheets
- applied design and copy file corrections
- applied photoshop manipulation
- working with multiple departments
- pre-press preparation, release to printer

EDUCATION

E-Tek Tech School, NJ — XHTML, XML, CSS, Flash, Dreamweaver, Acrobat — Certification DeutscheSprache Schule at United Nations International School, NYC — German Language (3yrs.) NYC Technical College Brooklyn, NY — Art & Advertising Design — AAS Degree Graphic Communications H.S., NYC — Graphic Design and Production